franchisesolutions.com 2016-06-03

# Franchise Solutions Privacy Policy

Effective Date: **4/10/2015**

This privacy policy applies to https://www.franchisesolutions.com owned and operated by Franchise Solutions. Franchise Solutions strongly believes in keeping your personally identifiable information confidential. Any information that you provide to us is used to enhance your experience at our web site and to help expedite the process of identifying a business opportunity that meets your criteria. 

Franchise Solutions has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](https://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiable information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, https://www.franchisesolutions.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

**Information Collection & Use:** When you request franchise information we will ask for your contact information such as name, email address and phone number. The inquiry forms that you complete are only forwarded to the specific franchise/business opportunity company(s) that you request additional information from. Franchise Solutions WILL NOT SELL, RENT OR SHARE your personally identifiable information with any other third parties except as described in this privacy policy. 

**Surveys or Contests:** From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or enhance our Web site.

**Newsletter Subscription and Membership:** If you submit a newsletter or membership subscription at Franchise Solutions, you will receive our franchise newsletter and you may receive member updates from time to time with franchise industry news and/or special promotions. If at any time you wish to stop receiving these e-mails, simply follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of the e-mail.

By submitting information to us and asking us to disclose your information to franchisors, you agree to receive telephone calls and/or emails about franchise opportunities even if you are registered with any state Do Not Call Registry, and/or the National Do Not Call List. 

**Testimonials:** From time to time, we will post testimonials on our site. We receive permission to post testimonials, prior to posting. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com).

**Blog:** Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. _To request removal of your personally identifiable information from our blog, contact us at[privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com)_. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Log Files:** As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

**Cookies:** A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

We use session ID cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser.

We also use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie allows us to remember you on successive visits to our site, allowing us to improve your experience.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

**Other Tracking Technologies:** Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Franchise Solutions and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removeing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click [here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

**Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting:** We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. To opt-out of interest-based ads on Google and Facebook, go to the [Digital Advertising Alliance](https://aboutads.info/choices) in the USA, [Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada](https://youradchoices.ca/) in Canada or the [European Digital Advertising Alliance](https://youronlinechoices.eu/) in Europe and select "Facebook Inc." and "Google Inc" from the list.

**Links to Other Sites:** This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Franchise Solutions. Please be aware that we, Franchise Solutions are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site.

**Social Media Widgets:** Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Access to Personally Identifiable Information:** If your personally identifiable information changes, please re-send your inquiry. We forward all information requests to our third party franchise professionals. Therefore, if your information should change or need to be edited, please resubmit your inquiry.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure:** We share your information with the franchises and business opportunities that you have expressed interest in. If you no longer want to receive information from a franchise, please contact that franchise directly.

**Service Providers:** We may employ third party companies to provide the services on our behalf such as chat support. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.

**Legal Disclaimer:** We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

**Business Transitions:** If Franchise Solutions is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information.

**Security:** We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com).

**Data Retention:** We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you services. If you wish to have your data removed or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Mobile Apps and Location Information:** When you download or use our mobile apps, you may give permission to share your device's real-time location (from cell towers or GPS). This information is used to provide services like localized search results. You can disable location-sharing at any time in your device settings. We also use an encrypted version of your device's unique device ID to track app usage, and to send any mobile alerts that you ask to receive. 

**Changes in this Privacy Policy:** If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contact Us**

15 Rye Street  
Suite 205  
Portsmouth, NH 03801

Your privacy is very important to us. If you have further questions or feedback, please e-mail us at [privacy@franchisesolutions.com](mailto:privacy@franchisesolutions.com)

Thank you for visiting Franchise Solutions.com,  
Matt Alden, President   
Franchise Solutions Inc.
